coned.com 2019-05-13

# Privacy Policy | Con Edison

Your privacy is important to us, so we protect the information we collect from you while doing business together. 

We obtain this information in several ways: through our websites, apps, and social media pages; your use of electric, gas, and/or steam services; any devices and technologies related to any energy efficiency, demand management, private generation, or other initiatives or programs we may offer to you from time to time; third-party sources, social media platforms, and in-person, phone, email, text, or written correspondence with you.

This information may include your name, account number, home or business address, email address, telephone number, energy use data (including but not limited to smart meter readings), location information, or other information that is specific to you as our customer or that you otherwise elect to share with us.

At the end of this Privacy Statement, we provide you with the opportunity to choose regarding our use and disclosure of your Customer Information to third-parties for marketing purposes. Customer Information includes your name, account number, home or business address, email address, and telephone number.

##  How We May Collect and Use Information 

We gather and use information to do business with you, including sending you bills, letting you know about products and services we offer, and addressing your questions or concerns.

We may use information from programs in which you voluntarily participate. Some of these programs have additional rules, which may contain additional conditions regarding how we may use and disclose your information. We recommend that you read any such rules carefully.

We may use your information for business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new product offerings and services, enhancing, improving or modifying our product offerings and services, identifying trends in energy use, developing and promoting programs and initiatives to encourage more efficient energy use and to manage demand for electricity, determining the effectiveness of our programs and promotional campaigns, and operating and expanding our business activities.

We may use information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate, to: (a) comply with requirements or directives of our governing regulatory agencies including, among others, the New York State Public Service Commission, the New Jersey Board of Public Utilities, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; (b) respond to requests from government or judicial authorities; (c) enforce our terms and conditions of service and applicable tariffs; (d) protect our operations or those of our affiliates; (e) protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (f) allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. We also may use your information to send or serve marketing communications, offers, and promotions that may be of interest, including on social media platforms.

We send occasional online surveys to gather information about your use of, and your opinion about, our programs and services, our energy related product offerings, and our websites and apps. Participation in our online surveys is voluntary. If you choose to participate, the information you provide will be used to improve our websites and apps and the programs, products, and services we offer to you.

##  How We May Share Information  

We may share information with our service providers or contractors in order to help us to do business with you, including processing payments, answering questions, developing and promoting programs, product offerings or services, or fulfilling your requests for a product or service.

We may share information with third-parties to permit them to send marketing communications or information about products and services that may be of interest, consistent with your choices. Also consistent with your choices, we may also share information with third-parties who provide energy-related products and services.

We may need to share information as we believe necessary and appropriate to: (a) comply with the requirements or directives of our governing regulatory agencies including, among others, the New York State Public Service Commission, the New Jersey Board of Public Utilities, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; (b) respond to requests from government or judicial authorities; (c) enforce our terms and conditions of service and applicable tariffs; (d) protect our operations or those of our affiliates; (e) protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (f) allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. We also may use your information to send marketing communications, offers, and promotions that may be of interest.

We may disclose information to a third-party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

##  Other Information We May Collect, Use, and Disclose

We use software to automatically collect other information that does not directly identify you. This information, such as the name of the domain or IP address where you access the Internet, the date and time when you access any of our websites, and the information that you view while using our services, is typically used for statistical purposes to help us to evaluate and improve our product offerings, services, and websites and apps, diagnose and correct technical problems, and detect fraud or other illegal activity and protect our systems.

We may also aggregate information so that it does not identify you or any other customer or user (for example, we may aggregate information to calculate the percentage of our customers who have a particular telephone area code). Please note that we may use and disclose this other information or aggregated information for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. 

Some of our website pages may use "cookies", i.e., small amounts of data that is stored on your computer or other device where you access the Internet to allow our websites to provide you with customized information, or to recall data so you don't have to retype it. We may use session ID cookies, which terminate when you close your Internet browser, or persistent cookies - a small text file stored on your computer's hard drive for an extended time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. You may also wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html>. However, if you do not accept these cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of our services. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer and provide personalized content. 

Pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) may be used to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Services (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns, and compile statistics about usage of the Services and response rates. 

We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other similar technologies to collect and analyze information about the use of the Services and report on activities and trends. The service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. Learn about [Google’s Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners) and [Google Analytics’ data practices](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

We may collect the physical location of the device you use to communicate with us. We may use your device's physical location to provide you with personalized location-based services and content. We may also share your device's physical location, combined with information about what advertisements you viewed and other information we collect, with our marketing partners to enable them to provide you with more personalized content. In some instances, you may allow or deny such uses and/or sharing of your device's location, but if you choose to deny such uses and/or sharing, we and/or our marketing partners may not be able to provide you with the applicable personalized services and content.

## Our Advertising

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads regarding goods and services that may be of interest to you when you access and use our websites and other websites, based on information relating to your use of our websites and other websites, on any of your devices. To do so, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through the use of pixel tags). They may also use these technologies, along with information they collect about your online use, to recognize you across the devices you use, such as a mobile phone and a laptop. Get [more information about this practice](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [learn how to opt out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/) of it in desktop and mobile browsers on the particular device on which you are accessing this Privacy Statement.

## Security

Con Edison has implemented policy guidelines and reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to help safeguard your information, from unauthorized access or improper use. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you believe your interaction with us is no longer secure, please contact us right away.

Con Edison's equipment and services are a part of our nation’s critical infrastructure; we are therefore vigilant about protecting our systems. Any electronic correspondence that you send to Con Edison, including email or any forms that you complete and transmit through our websites, may be monitored for suspected illegal activity and/or shared with regulatory, public or government agencies.

##  You Can Choose How We Use, Disclose, and Share Customer Information 

We give you choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Customer Information to other third-parties for their direct marketing purposes (except in circumstances required by law, regulation or order). If you would prefer that we do not share your Customer Information on a going-forward basis with other third-parties for their direct marketing purposes, you may opt-out of this sharing by:

  * unsubscribing from the list of Customer Information we would share with other third parties
  * unsubscribing directly from the emails sent to you by other third parties
  * calling [1-718-802-6079](tel:+17188026079)

##  Special Notes 

Links: This Privacy Statement does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third-parties, including any third-party operating any site or service linked to our websites. The inclusion of a link on our websites does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or our affiliates. Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, usage and disclosure policies and practices (including the data security practices) of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM, or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, web browser provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including any information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with our apps or social media accounts. 

**Children's Privacy** : We do not direct services to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and we request that these individuals do not provide information to us.

**Access and Update Your Data** : Contact us to request a copy of your energy use data, or to update any inaccurate or outdated Customer Information. We will seek to respond to your request for access or correction promptly. 

**Retention, Accuracy, and Data Quality** : We will retain information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. In addition, we take steps to keep information complete and accurate for its intended purpose.

**Modifications to this Privacy Statement** : Con Edison may modify this Privacy Statement from time to time to reflect legal, technological, or other developments. Any updates will appear on the Privacy Statement page. 

**Contact Us** : If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, or if you believe that we are not following the Privacy Statement as it is set forth here, contact us.

Updated August 6, 2018
